# INCONAINSHRA USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

mona.mishra20@icloud.com

(425)-306-9297

• Houston, TX

monamishra.com

linkedin.com/in/mona-mishra

### Personal statement

I am holistic user experience professional with a mind that is both creative and analytical. Having worked in the field that needs complex systems for expert users, my work has been driven by people and the stories I hear from them as well as from being in their context and experiencing scenarios myself. I learn by communicating and think by sketching. I value design aesthetic just as much as functional usability because good looking design enhances user experience from the start and establishes trust in the product. Mentorship has evolved me as a designer and I try to do the same for people who seek guidance and are new to this field.

#### Education

# University of Texas at Austin

MS in Information Studies, Specialization in User Experience(UX) Design Jan 2017 – Dec 2018 GPA: 4.0

### MIT, Pune

Bachelor in Engineering (BE), Computer Science Aug 2008 – May 2012 GPA: 3.5

#### Skills

# Design:

- Paper prototyping
- Rapid (clickable) prototyping
- Data Visualization
- Prototyping/Interaction tools:
  - Figma
  - Sketch/InVision
  - Adobe XD
  - Axure RP
  - Javascript/HTML/CSS

#### Research:

- In-depth interviews
- Expert reviews
- Competitive analysis of direct and indirect competitors
- Usability testing
- Customer journey maps

#### Plus [Programming]:

- Proficient in:
  - Java
  - JavaScript
  - HTML/CSS
  - MySql
- Familiar with:
  - ReactJS
  - Angular JSC/C++

# Work Experience

#### evoleap / UX/UI Designer

Aug 2020 - Present, Houston, TX

Leading design for a multiple software applications in a fast paced startup in Houston. Creating modern web based application to improve productivity and decision making in a field like oil and gas that relies on tired, old and clunky products. Managing research, project communication and co-creating activities with the developers and clients.

Leading design for a multiple software applications in a fast paced startup in Houston. Creating modern web based application to improve productivity and decision making in a field like oil and gas that relies on tired, old and clunky products.

#### ExxonMobil / UX Designer

Feb 2019 - May 2020, Spring, TX

Worked closely with a cross-functional team (located globally) in an agile framework, to identify requirements and design effective solutions for desktop and web application.

Identified complex problems by engaging in user research techniques to incorporate customer's voice in the design to inform high level solution.

Identified risks, prioritized user stories with stakeholders and defined usability metrics to understand the severity of a problem and eliminate assumptions.

Participated in project planning and sprint planning with the software development team to define long-term goals and desired outcomes in an agile environment.

#### Sentier Strategic Resources, LLC / UX Designer

Sep 2018 - Dec 2018, Austin, TX

Redesigned a real estate application using participatory and iterative design techniques and delivered a design system library to ensure easier and consistent design and development process.

Conducted usability tests for a retail client to identify usability issues and recommend solutions.

#### University of Texas at Austin / UX/UI Designer

Jun 2017 – Aug 2018, Austin, TX

Ideated and launched BeVote app for iPhone users that motivates students at UT Austin, to register and vote in an upcoming election and educates them about candidates and issues in their county.

Designed, developed and delivered an interactive web-based toolkit using front-end technologies like AngularJS and HTML/CSS.

Continued on page 2 ...

## Skills

#### Methods:

- User-centered Design and Design Thinking
- Storytelling

#### **Teamwork**

- Listening
- Communicating ideas and knowledge - Organizing and managing project

#### Other tools

- Proficient in:
  - Adobe Photoshop
  - Keynote
  - Adobe InDesign
  - Git
- Familiar with:
  - Tableau
  - Principle
  - Adobe Illustrator

#### More

Director: ASIS&T and AWIT UT Student Chapter (2017–18)

Teaching Assistant: Predictive Analysis and Data Mining, Finance and Algorithm

# Work Experience

### University of Memphis / Web Developer

Jun 2016 – Dec 2016, Memphis, TN

Designed and developed a JSP/JavaScript based online game to engage new students with the university.

Designed and developed a Learning Management System using Moodle framework to host two courses for a federal funded project.

# The Digital Group Infotech / Software Developer

Oct 2014 – Apr 2015, Pune, India

Sucessfully created a .Net and Oracle based web application, for clients whose businesses are set up on call center framework. Collaborated with developers to identify requirements, enhance supportability and identify performance bottlenecks.

# **QED Baton Enabled Services** / Demand Generation Executive

Sep 2012 – Sep 2013, Pune, India

Identified and developed new business opportunities for clients, with leading international corporation's executives and Business Development Managers.

